<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Jianfei Yang on Jianfei Yang (Rocky)</title>
    <link>https://marsyang.site/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dr. Jianfei Yang on Jianfei Yang (Rocky)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://marsyang.site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Group</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/group/</guid>
      <description>Open Positions I am hiring Ph.D. students (full scholarship) and visiting students (CSC or self-funded) regarding the following research topics:&#xA;Embodied AI: perception and action models for robotics Multimodal AI: large models (VLM/VLA) for robotics TinyML: edge AI models for robotics The candidates are expected to have solid backgrounds on machine learning, deep learning or embodied AI. Please drop an email to me with the title &amp;ldquo;PhD Application + [Name]&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/publications/</guid>
      <description>For a full list of publications, please visit my Google Scholar. I have stopped to update this page since early 2025.&#xA;Book Chapters, Survey and Library Video Unsupervised Domain Adaptation with Deep Learning: A Comprehensive Survey Yuecong Xu, Haozhi Cao, Zhenghua Chen, Xiaoli Li, Lihua Xie, Jianfei Yang* In ACM Computing Surveys (IF=23.6), 2024&#xA;SenseFi: A Library and Benchmark on Deep-Learning-Empowered WiFi Human Sensing&#xA;Jianfei Yang, Xinyan Chen, Dazhuo Wang, Han Zou, Chris Xiaoxuan Lu, Sumei Sun, Lihua Xie In Patterns, Cell Press, 2023</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/portrait/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/portrait/</guid>
      <description> Dr. Jianfei Yang&#xA;Assistant Professor (Tenure-Track)&#xA;Director of Multimodal embodied AI and Robotic Systems &amp;lt;MARS&amp;gt; Lab&#xA;School of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering School of Electrical and Electronic Engineering Nanyang Technological University, Singapore&#xA;Office: N3-02b-59, North Spine (N3), 50 Nanyang Avenue, 639798&#xA;Email: jianfei.yang (at) ntu.edu.sg </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/recruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/recruit/</guid>
      <description>Here is some information for prospective students and visitors. Thanks for your interest in joining my group! Due to the high volume of emails I receive, I may not be able to respond to each one individually. Please review the information below before contacting me. Thank you.&#xA;Prospective Ph.D. students: please email me with your CV, representative papers (if any), and a short research statement.&#xA;Prospective postdocs: please email me directly with your CV, and a research statement.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/award/</guid>
      <description> I am keen on participating academic and industrial AI challenges to deal with real-world data problems.&#xA;Recognition Forbes Asia 30 Under 30 List, Class 2024 Digileader by Digital Futures (RISE, Sweden), Class 2023 World’s Top 2% Scientists (Stanford), 2022-present Awards in Academia First place, ICCV-21 Masked Face Recognition Challenge First place, IEEE CVPR 2019 UG2+ Challenge - Zero-shot Detection in Rain (Award: $60K) First place, PHI-Net Challenge by Pacific Earthquake Engineering Research Center, Los Angelos, USA [News] Third place, IEEE CVPR 2020 EmotionNet Challenge First place, ACM ICMI 2018 Emotion Recognition Challenge, Colorado, USA NTU Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship Award (12/1000+) NTU EEE Best Thesis Award (2/400+) Awards in Industrial Challenges First place, WeChat Big Data Challenge - Multimodal Video Classification (Award: $60K) First place, Alibaba A-tech Challenge 2021 - Transaction Fraud Detection First place, DIGIX Global AI Challenge - Product Image Retrieval (Award: $35K) [News] First place, Xinye Cup 2021 - Intelligent Retail AI Solution (Award: $10K) First place, JD Global Data Challenge 2017 - Livestock face recognition (Award: $100K) [News] First place, HUAWEI Garbage Recognition Challenge (Award: $35K) [IEEE News] First place, Buildathon of Singapore by Ministry of Education Second place, Microsoft Imagine Cup 2017 (2/782) First place, China Mobile Internet of Things Hackathons (Award: $15K) Third place, National AI Challenge - Person Re-identification (Award: $35K) First place, Microsoft Beauty of Programming (BoP-16) Challenge by Microsoft Research Asia/IEEE (1/20000+) First place, Humanoid Robotics Hackathon by ALDEBARAN Awards in Subject Competition First Prize, National Mobile Internet Innovation Contest 2015 (China) First Prize, National Undergraduate IOT Design Contest 2014 by MOE (China) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friends</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/friends/</guid>
      <description>Seniors I am honored to have seniors who lend me a hand selflessly.&#xA;Dr. Han Zou - Research Scientist, Meta Dr. Zhenghua Chen - PI, Lab Head, A*star Dr. Kexin Guo - Associate Prof, BUAA Dr. Chen Wang - Assistant Prof, University at Buffalo Dr. Chris Xiaoxuan Lu - Associate Prof, UCL Juniors I am very happy to help my smart juniors, and grow up with them.&#xA;Dr. Yuecong Xu - Lecturer, NUS Dr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patents</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/patents/</guid>
      <description> PCT Patents (US) US12058213B2 (granted) - Device-Free Human Identification and Device-Free Gesture Recognition US12035166B2 (granted) - Unsupervised WiFi-Enabled Device-User Association for Personalized Location-based Service WO2024025469A1 (filed) - System for Determining Location of Device and Methods for Forming and Operating Thereof WO2024080929A1 (filed) - Method And System For Training A Neural Network Model To Perform Image Classification And Image Localization And/Or Segmentation Chinese Patents CN109359539B (granted) - Attention Assessment Method and Device, Terminal Equipment and Computer Readable Storage Medium CN108344416A (granted) - WiFi-based Localization Method based on Cartographic Information Auto-Matching Target NTU Technical Disclosures 2022-093 - Human Respiration Sensing System based on WiFi Signals 2022-137 - A Localization Approach Based On Variational Inference Using IMU And WiFi RSS 2022-138 - Advanced Particle Swarm Optimization To Localization With IMU And WiFi Measurements, And The Development Of Sensing Platform </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests My research mainly focuses on Physical AI, where AI enables physical systems—such as robotics, IoT, and embodied agents—to perceive, reason, and interact with the real world. Broadly speaking, I study how AI models enhance robotic perception and decision-making with multimodal sensor inputs (i.e. Multimodal AI, LLM, and VLA), how robots can personalize their behavior by understanding human states and interactions (i.e. Human-Centered Embodied AI), how foundation models can be efficiently deployed on edge devices to support real-time robotic perception and control (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/services/</guid>
      <description> Professional Appointments Assistant Professor, MAE/EEE, Nanyang Technological University, 2024-present Visiting Scholar, John A. Paulson School Of Engineering And Applied Sciences, Harvard University, 2024 Visiting Scholar, RIKEN AIP / the University of Tokyo, 2024 Presidential Postdoctoral Fellow, PI, Nanyang Technological University, 2021-2023 Senior Research Engineer, BEARS, University of California, Berkeley, 2020-2021 Editorial Service Associate Editor, IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems, 2024-present Associate Editor, Neurocomputing (Elsevier), 2024-present Area Chair / Track Chair (Conference) International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2024 IEEE International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Systems (ICPADS) 2024 Conference PC Member The Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022-2023 The Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2020-2024 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2022-2024 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2024 European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2022 The International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2021-2024 AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020-2024 International Conference on Computer Communications and Networks (ICCCN) 2024 IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference (WCNC) 2021, 2022, 2023 Conference and Workshop Organizer IEEE ICCCN 2024, 1st International Workshop on &amp;ldquo;Integrated Sensing, Communication, and Computing in IoT Systems&amp;rdquo; IEEE CVPR 2024, 7th UG2+ Challenge on &amp;ldquo;UDA Tracking and Pose Estimation&amp;rdquo; IEEE CVPR 2022, 5th UG2+ Prize Challenge IJCAI 2021, 3nd International Workshop on &amp;ldquo;Deep Learning for Human Activity Recognition&amp;rdquo; Journal Reviewer Service Reviewer, IEEE Internet of Things Journal Reviewer, IEEE Wireless Communications Magazine Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Artificial Intelligence Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Multimedia Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology Reviewer, IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computational Intelligence Reviewer, IEEE Robotics and Automation Reviewer, IEEE Systems Journal Reviewer, IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters Reviewer, ACM Transactions on Spatial Algorithm and Systems, Pattern Recognition Reviewer, International Journal of Distributed Sensor Network Reviewer, Elsivier - Information Fusion Reviewer, Elsivier - Knowledge-based Systems Reviewer, Elsivier - Expert Systems with Applications Reviewer, Elsivier - Computer Vision and Image Understanding Reviewer, Elsivier - Digital Signal Processing Reviewer, Elsivier - Advanced Engineering Informatics Reviewer, Elsivier - Neurocomputing Reviewer, Elsivier - Energy and Buildings Reviewer, Hindawi - Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Template</title>
      <link>https://marsyang.site/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marsyang.site/template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this article is to make sure that all basic HTML Elements are decorated with CSS so as to not miss any possible elements when creating new themes for Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
